<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: karthik | Manufacturing Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/categories/karthik/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-20T09:56:21+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[System Insights]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green Supply Chain Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2013/08/20/green-supply-chains/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T12:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2013/08/20/green-supply-chains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Designing and implementing sustainable supply chains is gaining importance these days, as depleting natural resources and increasing climate change risks have emphasized the need for eco-friendly manufacturing practices. The process of integrating environmental drivers into Supply Chain Management (SCM) is called Green Supply Chain Management. Green Supply Chain Management is motivated by:</p>

<ul>
<li>Diminishing raw materials</li>
<li>Increased material waste and disposal</li>
<li>Increasing environmental awareness among stake holders</li>
<li>Being competitive among peers</li>
</ul>


<p>Green Supply Chain Management focuses on identifying and minimizing the wastes generated in entire supply chain process. The waste reduction strategy could be long term or short term. The long term options are more strategic and the short term options are more tactical.</p>

<h3>Implementing Green Supply Chains</h3>

<p>Greening the supply chain involves the following processes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Green Design &ndash; Designing a product/service that is environmentally sustainable</li>
<li>Green Purchase &ndash; Selecting a product/service that will minimise negative environmental impact over the life cycle</li>
<li>Green Manufacturing &ndash; Implementing manufacturing processes which lead to a reduction in energy consumption, resource consumption, waste by-products, and water usage</li>
<li>Green Distribution &ndash; Reducing environmental impacts in packaging and logistics</li>
<li>Reverse Logistics &ndash; Retreiving the product from the end consumer for the purposes of capturing value or proper disposal</li>
</ul>


<h3>Benefits</h3>

<ul>
<li>Improves environmental efficiency</li>
<li>Increase reuse/recycle of waste</li>
<li>Reduces waste for disposal</li>
<li>Raw material and resource conservation</li>
<li>Improves cost competitiveness</li>
<li>Reduce GHG emission levels</li>
</ul>


<h3>How vimana helps</h3>

<p>System Insights develops <a href="http://systeminsights.com/vimana">vimana</a>, the predictive analytics platform for manufacturing intelligence. System Insights delivers compelling value to manufacturing enterprises across multiple verticals around the world, by increasing asset utilization, reducing operational costs, and improving profitability. Enhancing manufacturing sustainability is one of the key values that vimana delivers. vimana provides visibility into manufacturing processes and process flows and helps identify and reduce waste in the value stream and supply chain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
