<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: vimana | Manufacturing Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://systeminsights.github.com/blog/categories/vimana/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://systeminsights.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-11T14:33:23+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://systeminsights.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[System Insights]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why SaaS?]]></title>
    <link href="http://systeminsights.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/why-saas/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T11:16:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://systeminsights.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/why-saas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A common question that we always get is why vimana is a software-as-a-service (SaaS) product. Surely, given how much data we are collecting, it must be easier to run it locally inside a plant, right? Well, if all vimana was doing was creating plots of part counts and utilization, then yes, running it locally does make sense. But vimana does a lot more -- it helps understand the patterns behind productivity (and the lack thereof), and being able to support these capabilities requires a whole lot more of computational resources.</p>

<p>So lets dig deeper -- why SaaS?</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Keep it Growing</strong>: SaaS allows us to scale product functionality as your operations grow. This means that vimana can scale to support an increasing number of devices, along with the analytical capabilities required to support them. SaaS also allows us to keep the app at the latest version without requiring long downtimes for the updates.</li>
<li><strong>Keep it All</strong>: SaaS allows us to keep historical plant data securely for as long as you want us to. This makes it possible to baseline against historical data to put current performance in context, and to make better decisions about the future based on past usage and operational patterns.</li>
<li><strong>Keep it Lean</strong>: SaaS enables simple, annual, pay-as-you-go pricing, where you pay based on the number of devices you have connected to vimana, and the kind of analysis being performed on the devices. Since the app is delivered over the web, any number of users can access it (even simultaneously!).</li>
</ol>


<p>SaaS deployments also allow us to farm out specific analytical processes to elastic clusters, using map reduce and other big-data-crunching technologies. We will be talking about this in detail in upcoming posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[McKinsey on (Manufacturing) Big Data - Part 2 - What do do with it]]></title>
    <link href="http://systeminsights.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/McKinsey-Part-2-What-do-do-with-it/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T13:47:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://systeminsights.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/McKinsey-Part-2-What-do-do-with-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are back studying McKinsey's report on Big Data following the last post, and here lets take a closer look at what we can do with Big Data. The report identifies several "levers" where data can be used to improve manufacturing performance (see below), and of these levers, we are primarily interested in these two:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-03-21-McKinsey-Part-2-What-do-do-with-it-levers.png"></p>

<ol>
<li>Implementing Lean Manufacturing (#5)</li>
<li>Using sensor data-driven operations analytics (#6)</li>
</ol>


<p>Lets look at the first of these in this post.</p>

<h2>Lean Manufacturing and the Digital Factory</h2>

<p>McKinsey identifies using Big Data to "create process transparency, develop dashboards, and visualize bottlenecks". Our vimana application is one example of applying Big Data to create realtime dashboards of manufacturing equipment (to learn more about vimana, please visit www.systeminsights.com/vimana.) The idea here is to provide a shopfloor user both a high-level "macro" view of the shopfloor, as well as a low-level "micro" view of a single device.  Questions the dashboards can help answer include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Which devices are producing parts today?</li>
<li>Which parts are being made right now?</li>
<li>How many parts have I made?</li>
<li>What has my device been doing today?</li>
<li>What is my efficiency?</li>
<li>Why have I been in a downtime?
  (This is a much more interesting question to answer than just "What are my downtimes". Knowing <em>why</em> downtimes occur can directly help in reducing or eliminating the downtimes, and is a step beyond simply knowing <em>that</em> a has downtime occurred).</li>
</ul>


<p>The data for vimana is streamed using the MTConnect Agent associated with each machine tool. The application itself runs in the cloud, aggregating hundreds of events every second from each machine tool. The analysis is done in realtime, and the visualizations are rendered instantly. Process transparency is achieved here because the application serves as a central repository of what is going on in the shopfloor, and multiple stakeholders (production, engineering, maintenance, management) can all use it to support decisions that come under their purview. This also takes us one step closer to the Digital Factory, where detailed operational data from the factory equipment is applied in building a complete digital model of the factory's operations, which can then be applied in optimizing its performance.</p>

<p><em>Macro Dashboard: Shopfloor</em>
<img class="center" src="/images/2012-03-21-McKinsey-Part-2-What-do-do-with-it-dashboard.png"></p>

<p><em>Micro Dashboard: Device</em>
<img class="center" src="/images/2012-03-21-McKinsey-Part-2-What-do-do-with-it-details.png"></p>

<p>Coming back to McKinsey, they estimate a reduction of 10 to 50% in costs from applying Big Data to implement Lean Manufacturing and the Digital Factory, accompanied by a marginal increase in revenue (2%). We have already seen vimana helping improve device utilization by over 25%, which directly leads to cost reductions. The real impact of Big Data here is not as much as in enabling us to ask new questions about a shop's productivity, but in helping us find even better answers for the same questions we have been asking for a long time and thus driving down costs. Of course, thats not to say that we cannot ask new questions based on the data –this is where data specifically from ubiquitous and low cost sensors can play a role, which we will examine in a future post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
