<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: energy | Manufacturing Big Data]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/categories/energy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-11T10:44:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[System Insights]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top Manufacturing Energy Consumers: A Close Look at the Paper Industry]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2013/05/30/energy-consumption-in-manufacturing/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T12:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2013/05/30/energy-consumption-in-manufacturing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jes%C3%BAs-nieto-gonz%C3%A1lez/30/a92/943/">Jesus Nieto Gonzalez</a> from the UC Berkeley Haas School of Business Class of 2014 worked with us on a research project to identify the top energy consumers in the manufacturing sector. Here are some of his findings:</p>

<ul>
<li>The top five energy-intensive industries are Paper, Petroleum and Coal products, Nonmetallic Mineral Products, Chemicals, and Primary Metals (measured based on BTU/$ output)</li>
<li>The paper industry has the highest electricity consumption as well, followed by Primary Metals and Textile Mills (measured based on kWH/$)</li>
<li>The EU countries (particularly Italy and Germany) have some of the highest electricity costs for Industrial consumers, followed by the BRIC countries and the US</li>
<li>The paper industry offers a lot of opportunities for energy efficiency and electrical energy reduction. The industry is highly fragmented and the major paper producers are concentrated in parts of the world with high electricity costs.</li>
</ul>


<p>The entire report is available <a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manufacturingbigdata-blog-static/pdfs/jesus-nieto-energy-consumption.pdf">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy Regulations in Tamil Nadu, India]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/07/10/tneb-regulations/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T11:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/07/10/tneb-regulations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Industrial energy consumers in Tamil Nadu, India have seen a sharp increase in energy costs beginning from April 2012. In this post we look at the revised tariff of the Tamil Nadu Electricity Board (TNEB), and examine its impact on the overall energy costs for a manufacturing plant.</p>

<h2>The Tariff</h2>

<p>The revised Tariff for Industrial Consumers (HT1A) is as follows (available <a href="http://tnerc.tn.nic.in/orders/Tariff%20Order%202009/2012/T.O%20No.%201%20of%202012%20dated%2030-03-2012.pdf">here</a>):</p>

<h3>Basic Charges</h3>

<ul>
<li>Demand Charges &mdash; INR 300 / kVA / month</li>
<li>Energy Charges &mdash; INR 5.50 / kWh</li>
</ul>


<h3>Restrictions and Surchages</h3>

<h4>Power Factor:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Power Factor => 0.9 &mdash; No Surcharge</li>
<li>0.9 > Power Factor => 0.85    &mdash; 1% of Current Consumption Charges for every 0.01 reduction in PF from 0.9</li>
<li>0.85 > Power Factor => 0.75 &mdash; 1.5% of Current Consumption Charges for every 0.01 reduction in PF from 0.9</li>
<li>Power Factor &lt; 0.75 &mdash; 2% of Current Consumption Charges for every 0.01 reduction in PF from 0.9</li>
</ul>


<h4>Billable Demand:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Demand Charges will levied on Maximum Demand that has actually been registered for the month or 90% of the Sanctioned Demand, whichever is higher.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Peak Hour:</h4>

<ul>
<li>HT Industrial Consumers will be billed 20% extra on the Energy Charges for the Energy recorded during the Peak hours</li>
<li>Duration of Peak hours will be 6:00am to 9:00am &amp; 6:00pm to 9:00pm</li>
</ul>


<h4>Night Hour:</h4>

<ul>
<li>HT Industrial Consumers will get a reduction of 5% on the Energy Charges for the Energy recorded during the Night hours</li>
<li>Duration of Night hour will be 10:00pm to 5:00am</li>
</ul>


<h4>Demand Integration Period:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Maximum Demand Integration period will be 15minutes</li>
</ul>


<h4>Harmonics:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Total Voltage Harmonic Distortion should not exceed 5%</li>
<li>Total Current Harmonic Distortion should not exceed 8%</li>
<li>If the harmonics level are not within the limits, then the consumer has to pay 15% of respective tariff as Compensation</li>
</ul>


<h2>Power Scenario in the State</h2>

<p>The state of Tamil Nadu has installed capacity of 10,364.5 MW and the average power availability is about 8500 MW. The demand ranges from 11,500 MW to 12,500 MW which gives a clear indication that the state has a shortage about 3000 to 4000 MW of power. Moreover if we see the growth of consumers, it keeps increasing at a rate of 5% every year. Because of this gap between demand and supply, TNEB has taken the following mitigation measures:</p>

<ul>
<li>40% cut on demand and energy for High Tension Industrial and Commercial Services</li>
<li>Load shedding of 2 hrs in Chennai and its suburbs</li>
<li>Load shedding of 4 hrs in other urban and rural areas</li>
<li>10% of power supply during Peak hours for Industrial and Commercial Services</li>
<li>Power Holiday for all HT &amp; LT consumers</li>
</ul>


<p>These restrictions can be relaxed based on the power availability. However, HT consumers are allowed to make power purchase to inter- and intra-state Open Access providers where cheaper power may be available.</p>

<h2>So&hellip; What&rsquo;s the Impact?</h2>

<p>Lets examine how these revised prices impact an average manufacturing plant.</p>

<p>Lets consider a Manufacturing Facility, with the following cost structure:</p>

<ul>
<li>Permitted Demand: 1000 kVA</li>
<li>Permitted Energy Quota: 300,000 kWh</li>
</ul>


<p>Based on this structure, lets assume that the energy consumed and the costs incurred during a representative month is as follows:</p>

<iframe width='410' height='500' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AjFwRioMlxbbdEptNTRoLVdtQUpsa1pIMW9NSXl5S1E&single=true&gid=0&output=html&widget=true'></iframe>


<p>Lets see how costs change with the new pricing under different scenarios:</p>

<h3>Case 1: Grid Only</h3>

<p>The revised grid costs are Rs. 5.50/kWh and the plant faces a 40% reduction on its demand and energy limits. The revised permitted demand is 600 kVA and the permitted energy is 180,000 kWH. The plant is penalized at twice the price for exceeding the energy or demand limits.</p>

<iframe width='410' height='600' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AjFwRioMlxbbdEptNTRoLVdtQUpsa1pIMW9NSXl5S1E&single=true&gid=1&output=html&widget=true'></iframe>


<p>If the plant is purely dependent on the grid (EB), then monthly energy costs grow by more than 120% (more than doubles!!!).</p>

<h3>Case 2: Grid and Diesel</h3>

<p>If the plant offsets 500 kVA of demand and 130,000 kWh of energy by running a diesel generator, which costs Rs. 15/kWh:</p>

<iframe width='410' height='650' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AjFwRioMlxbbdEptNTRoLVdtQUpsa1pIMW9NSXl5S1E&single=true&gid=2&output=html&widget=true'></iframe>


<p>Even with using an auxilliary Diesel Generator to supplement grid energy, the plant spends 82% more on energy.</p>

<h3>Case 3: Grid and Power Purchase</h3>

<p>The plant purchases 130,000 kWh at Rs. 8/kWh, and gets a equivalent deemed demand of 260 kVA:</p>

<iframe width='410' height='700' frameborder='0' src='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AjFwRioMlxbbdEptNTRoLVdtQUpsa1pIMW9NSXl5S1E&single=true&gid=3&output=html&widget=true'></iframe>


<p>The plant still sees an increase of about 60% after purchasing power from third party suppliers.</p>

<h2>What do we do?</h2>

<p>Its clear that there are no simple ways of reducing or even maintaining energy costs at the &ldquo;pre-hike&rdquo; levels in Chennai. Simply changing the energy source to Diesel is not an option either, and buying third-party power can be just as expensive as using energy from the TNEB grid. What this calls for is more aggressive and hands-on management of energy consumption in the manufacturing facility, looking at which machines and systems consume the most energy, and finding ways to decrease their usage. Our vimana platform does just this and we will be back with a followup post on how <a href="http://www.systeminsights.com/vimana">vimana</a> can be applied in improving energy efficiency and reducing energy costs in a manufacturing facility.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BEC Article in Livebetter Magazine]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/06/08/livebetter-article/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T08:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/06/08/livebetter-article</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The June issue of the <a href="http://livebettermagazine.com">Livebetter Magazine</a> features an article about the BEC standard by Ralph Resnick from the National Center for Defense Manufacturing and Machining and myself. You can read the article <a href="http://livebettermagazine.com/eng/magazine/article_detail.lasso?id=307">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presentation on Baseline Energy Consumption]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/02/16/Presentation-on-BEC/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-16T23:22:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/02/16/Presentation-on-BEC</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following up to the previous posts (here and here) on Baseline Energy Consumption, here is a presentation about the standard:</p>

<script src="http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4f3dd5bcdf5d29001f0047d8.js"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baseline Energy Consumption - Case Study 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/02/08/BEC-Case-Study-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T02:36:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.manufacturingbigdata.com/blog/2012/02/08/BEC-Case-Study-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The BEC standard discussed in the last post was applied in comparing the performance of three similar small-sized Lathes. The three devices were as follows (all brand names anonymized to protect the innocent!):</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-02-08-BEC-Case-Study-1-A.png"></p>

<p>The test conditions were as follows:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-02-08-BEC-Case-Study-1-B.png"></p>

<p>The BEC metric for the three devices is as follows:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-02-08-BEC-Case-Study-1-C.png"></p>

<p>Here is how the metric looks broken down into its components:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-02-08-BEC-Case-Study-1-D.png"></p>

<p>The results showed that Device A consumes significantly less energy than Device B and Device C. Extrapolating the BEC metric, the estimated annual energy usage for these machine tools can be calculated assuming that each device operates for 8,000 hours per year at a cost of US $0.09 per kWh of energy; similarly, the Carbon Footprint of the devices is also calculated, assuming a footprint of 0.6 kg CO2-eq/kWh. As we can see in the table below, selecting Device A saves more than $800/year compared to Device C, and $400/year compared to Device B.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/2012-02-08-BEC-Case-Study-1-E.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
